Hugo Puhlmann

Software Developer

Passionate and technical Software Developer with a strong sense of code quality and design. Three years of professional experience as a sotware developer, including two years in the games industry and one at an integrated circuits company. Currently working with games in spare time and very eager for a chance to again extend this joy to a full-time job. Living in Brazil and hoping for the oportunity to relocate to another country and be part of a different culture.

Skills

Advanced Extensive experience with C++, C#, version control software (especially git), and Unity3D.

Intermediate Experience with Python and Java for desktop application development. Strong mathematical skills, mostly in linear algebra, calculus and analytical geometry. Experience with Lua and Löve2D game framework.

Basic Understanding of game engine architecture, computer graphics and OpenGL.

Languages Native portuguese speaker. Fluent spoken and written english.

Experience

2010–2012 Researcher, Group of Mobile Computing Systems (GMob), UFSM, Santa Maria.

Member of a mobile computing research group, developed a few prototype applications for Android and J2ME devices.

2012–2013 Game Programmer, Decadium Studios/IMGNATION Studios, Santa Maria.

Worked using Unity and C# to develop two mobile games, NBB Game (Aquiris Studios, Sports) and Dodge This! (IMGNATION Studios, Action). Responsibilities included mainly UI and gameplay coding.

2013–2014 IT Analyst/Programmer, Santa Maria Design House (SMDH), Santa Maria.

2014–Present **Software Development & IT – Team Leader**, Santa Maria Design House (SMDH), Santa

Maria.

Responsible for the development of compilers, hardware emulators and other development tools for proprietary microcontrollers. Main tools used are C++ and C#.

2014-Present Independent Games, http://hstefan.com/demos.

Game demos and remakes of classic games.

2009-Present Misc. Projects, https://github.com/hstefan.

Mostly utilities and experiments.

Education and Awards

2009–2013 Bachelor of Computer Science, Universidade Federal de Santa Maria, UFSM.

2011 ACM ICPC Competition, ACM-ICPC.

40th place in the 2011 Brazilian finals